mobile: 980-322-7843 jason@jasonsilverstein.com

## **Executive Summary**

**Experienced digital executive known for building businesses, flexible teams, and engaging products and services.** Proven track record of learning markets, identifying opportunities, creating strategies, and leading changes to support and grow business. Promote transparency, communication skills, forming relationships, and accountability by employing adaptable teams and methods.

### Experience

#### SR. VICE PRESIDENT, ACBJ — CHARLOTTE, NC / 2009-PRESENT

American City Business Journals is one of the nation's premier publishers of local business, sports and auto news, employing 1,600 in over 40 cities. Digital Operations is its business unit responsible for centrally building, designing, optimizing, and supporting the company's consumer products and platform technologies. As executive leading the 41-person business unit, contributions include:

- Product/Technology Platform Vision. Accepted leadership for legacy infrastructure, teams, and
  products, then undertook a complete infrastructure rewrite and team reorganization to meet
  anticipated business needs. Introduced technical and product roadmaps, continuous delivery and
  iteration. Enterprise improvements continue, including nearing completion of a full product suite rerelease, better MVC models, frameworks, rebuilt tools, version control, and more.
- **Culture Changes and Team Investment.** Built a team comfortable with adaptive changes as business needs evolve. Started by hiring key managers, then helped create team-oriented culture. Turned high turnover rate into a more stable, focused team. Continually invest personally, via managers, or external groups to keep technology and personal skills updated for changing digital environments.
- Economies of Scale, Scope and Labor. During unprecedented digital growth, continue to institute operational efficiencies yet grow resources responsibly. Built and support over 300 products, including responsive websites, mobile apps, and email newsletters. Simultaneously supported public site traffic growth of over 317 percent (page-views) and 253 percent (unique visitors) in last five years. Rebuilt commerce platform grew 200 percent in transactional revenue during same period. A new, in-house CMS reduced administrative production work by over 100 man-weeks per year across 43 newsrooms.
- **Process Flexibility and Leadership.** In 2009, the company needed the division's product model to shift from a stand-alone unit to having product development to serve as service bureau to the enterprise. The change increased inbound request origins from one unit executive's team to six ACBJ executives, 40 publishers and their staffs, and direct access from a new unit. An updated ticketing system and process changes absorbed the over 100 percent increase in requests.
- Corporate Communications and Fiscal Responsibility. Represent highest technology escalation point for ACBJ employees with respect to digital products. Have served as binding, legal authority in external matters. Speak at conferences and internal business unit meetings regularly on the state of our technology operations. Own divisional P&L and continue to meet financial standards for accountability and ethics regarding budgeted expenses and cross-divisional resource needs.

# Jason Silverstein

mobile: 980-322-7843 jason@jasonsilverstein.com

• Continued Role and Responsibility Expansion. Hired initially for a specific business unit and now serve all business units via Digital Operations division. Work with parent company Advance in areas where technology must be in different compliance requirements. Examples include vendor procurement, security compliance needs, and corporate disaster recovery standards.

#### VICE PRESIDENT, CHARLOTTE OBSERVER — CHARLOTTE, NC / 2007-09

Led the Interactive division's teams, created and enhanced the company's digital products, managed the division's \$18M P&L as well as traffic/distribution performance. During tenure, finished first in two national news website design awards. Interactive team and newsroom combined to be most award-winning digital staff in NC. Also introduced new products in social, mobile and Kindle products.

#### CHIEF OF STAFF/VARIOUS TITLES, YAHOO! INC — DALLAS, TX / 2000-07

Started as Technical Yahoo!, then served as Professional Services Manager, Sr. Program Manager, and lastly as Chief of Staff / Director of Business Operations for the global audio and video delivery division. Led integrations of multiple acquisitions, including LAUNCH, MusicMatch, and flickr (video). Managed domestic and international audio/video data center operation expansions, including on-site Beijing launch. Created new white-label products for Fortune 500 clients while leading consulting unit.

#### CO-FOUNDER, SPORTSTATIONS.COM — DALLAS, TX / 1999-2000

Co-founded online media company that, with institutional, venture capital, plus friends and family funding, hired 60 FTEs that created sport-specific communities for athletic participants.

#### EARLY CAREER — 1995-99

Progressed through a variety of roles, including work for the <u>National Basketball Association</u> and Tar Heel Sports Network ("THSN"). At THSN, earned first management job and led internet, television and radio products for the University of North Carolina athletic department.

#### Education

<u>Southern Methodist University</u> - MBA (Information Technology & Operations Management), 2004 <u>University of North Carolina</u> - Chemistry, 1995; Electronic Communications, 1996

# Community Involvement

<u>F3</u> - Board of Directors, 2011-Present. Oversee Technology and Product Development for 3,000+ person volunteer organization that drives men's community involvement across 10 states and over 400 locations.